Tejas Goyal

#Sales & Marketing Strategy #Business Development #Key Account Management

Contact

Address GJ, 382443

Phone 777 300 9828

E-mail tejas889@gmail.com

LinkedIn

<u>www.linkedin.com/in/te asgoyal</u>

Skills

Business development and planning

Very Good

Channel Management

Very Good

Strategy development

Very Good

Product and service sales

Very Good

Market Positioning

Very Good

Client communication

Business driven and strategic thinker – Sales and Marketing manager highly regarded for analytical and decision-making skill to achieve revenue driven growth, with an experience of eight years in handling B2B customers for city gas distribution and managing channel sales for oil marketing company.

Work History

Regional Sales Manager (May 2018 – Present) (Region -West, Central, East India)

Raychem RPG, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

- Portfolio handled Currently looking after the West and East part of India which is approx. 48 Cr
- **Stakeholder management** Major customers City Gas Distribution (CGD) companies, and we offer gas metering solution Smart gas meters and Mechanical meters for Domestic and Commercial. Market presence of 54 %.
 - Corrosion protection services Heat shrink sleeves, epoxy coatings to Oil and Gas industry
- Drive business performance by strategizing to achieve business objective I was able to give a growth of 43 % which contributes to additional 23 Cr business.
- **Business Development** Scouting markets like middle east and western Asia which have huge potential for both Smart gas metering solution and commercial applications.
- Brand Management Participate in various conference and exhibition, seamless execution to booth management, successfully converted few enquires to orders.
- **Identifying customer needs** Influencing various stakeholders in hierarchy, which includes influencers and decision-makers assisting at various stages of buying cycle.
- Commercial and Economic acumen We monitor price trend, analyze competitor's strategy and future technological changes, in collaboration with product management team try to incorporate changes.
- **Maximizing value** old payment recovery, managing expired bank guarantees, GST realizations which directly impact the bottom line.

Territory Sales Manager (Sept 2015 – May2018)

Nayara Energy, Indore, Madhya Pradesh

• Channel partner management Was responsible for 32 channel partners, sales growth of 8.5% with existing network year on year.

Hobbies

Reading – Fiction and non-fiction

Cycling

Traveling

Cooking

- **Developing a sales plan for the territory** Sales plan was the most significant part of supply chain planning and was planned on a micro level to get the exact picture of the whole financial year.
- Business Development Process adherence, abide to regulatory norms during construction or development on a retail outlet, proposing nonfuel retailing (NFR) services.
- Marketing Activation key initiatives to spread awareness, running single-day campaigns and small meets.
- Managing customer experience Training and Development Regular training sessions forecourt staff, inculcate a customer centric approach which justify brand value.
- Facilitate our franchise in regular audits Audits and checks at regular interval on retail outlet to adhere to marketing guidelines and local norms, identifying key improvement areas to create value.

Summer Intern (March 2014 – May 2014)

Bharat Petroleum Corporation limited, Jodhpur, Rajasthan

Problem statement was to identify challenges faced in sales of lubricant at retail outlets, and during my brief tenure we were able to identify few significant gaps which include need of training on lubricants to workforce at outlets, proper branding in line with product requirement based on local needs.

Purchase Engineer (June 2010 -Sept 2011)

Ratnamani Metals and tubes Ltd., Anjar, Gujarat

- Negotiate with suppliers on lead-time, cost, and quality to obtain the maximum benefit for the company.
- Ensure commercial, legal and contractual compliances in all the procurement transactions.
- Create monthly performance reviews and reports focusing on overall sourcing requirements.
- Analyze all suppliers to select the most suitable suppliers who can deliver high-quality products at competitive pricing.

Accomplishments

- Was awarded best performer award for two consecutive quarters in FY 21
- Was awarded with Top Learner award in the Oil and Gas division
- Vice presidents' appreciation award for payment recovery of legacy cases held from last 24 months.
- Recognition award for market activation.
- Recognition award for the highest secondary sales of lubricants.

Certifications

Sept 2021	Inbound Marketing by HubSpot
Sept 2021	SEO by HubSpot
April 2020	Google Analytics for Beginners
May 2020	Advanced Google Analytics

Education

2013 – 2015 MBA: Marketing

Pandit Deendayal Energy University - Gandhinagar

2006 - 2010 Bachelor of Engineering: Mechanical

Bachelor of Engineering: Mechanical Engineering

Saurashtra University - Rajkot